<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Projects on Roudranil</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Roudranil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Roudranil Das |</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 21:58:18 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://roudranil.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Forests and Deforestation</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/visualisation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 09:23:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/visualisation/</guid><description>Synopsis In this project we explore the trends of deforestation in the past 3 decades. We use visualisation techniques in order to find patterns behind deforestation and it&amp;rsquo;s driving factors. Following this, we attempt to answer questions regarding conversion of forests to land for other purposes and questions regarding Brazil&amp;rsquo;s excessive loss of forest cover. Then we aim to develop a dashboard to explore the above posed questions.
Report: link</description></item><item><title>Financial Literacy among 18-35 year olds</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/financial-literacy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 22:27:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/financial-literacy/</guid><description>Synopsis We conduct a survey where we test the respondent&amp;rsquo;s knowledge on 4 aspenct: financial knowledge and skills, financial attitude and knowledge about inflation and other parameters. Using these we attempt to judge their financial literacy.
This project is being conducted by by 5 first year MSc. Data Science students at the Chennai Mathematical Institute: Me, Adarsha Mondal, Shreyan Chakraborty, Deepmalya Dutta and Ujan Dasgputa.
The project is in progress. More information will be added at a later point of time.</description></item><item><title>Bayesian Analysis of Efficacy of the ChAd0x1 nCoV-19 (AZD1222) Vaccine</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/dissertation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 22:00:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/dissertation/</guid><description>Synopsis 2020 saw the onset of the onset of the Covid-19 pandemic cause by the SARS-CoV-2 virus. With the number of daily affected people and number of deaths due to the pandemic climbing sharply, a vaccine was the need of the hour. In this paper we consider one such vaccine, the ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 (AZD1222) vaccine (known as Covishield in India), and we investigate its efficacy based on studies of four randomised controlled trials held in Brazil, South Africa, and the United Kingdom.</description></item></channel></rss>