<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Roudranil</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Roudranil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Roudranil Das |</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 09:00:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://roudranil.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Audio Classification with CNN-LSTM networks</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/audio-classification/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 09:00:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/audio-classification/</guid><description>Synopsis In this project, I aim to classify 1 second long audio clips of the words &amp;ldquo;one&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;two&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;three&amp;rdquo;, &amp;hellip;, &amp;ldquo;zero&amp;rdquo;. The data for this project is taken from the TensorFlow Speech Recognition Challenge. However I have slightly deviated from the competition, in terms of the target classes, where I have truncated the target classes to the ones I mentioned above.
I trained 3 models on the data:
A baseline CNN model ==========================================================================================
Layer (type:depth-idx) Output Shape Param # ==========================================================================================
BaseModel [128, 10] -- ├─convblock: 1-1 [128, 16, 65, 23] -- │ └─Sequential: 2-1 [128, 16, 65, 23] -- │ │ └─Conv2d: 3-1 [128, 16, 130, 46] 160 │ │ └─ReLU: 3-2 [128, 16, 130, 46] -- │ │ └─MaxPool2d: 3-3 [128, 16, 65, 23] -- ├─convblock: 1-2 [128, 32, 33, 12] -- │ └─Sequential: 2-2 [128, 32, 33, 12] -- │ │ └─Conv2d: 3-4 [128, 32, 67, 25] 4,640 │ │ └─ReLU: 3-5 [128, 32, 67, 25] -- │ │ └─MaxPool2d: 3-6 [128, 32, 33, 12] -- ├─convblock: 1-3 [128, 64, 17, 7] -- │ └─Sequential: 2-3 [128, 64, 17, 7] -- │ │ └─Conv2d: 3-7 [128, 64, 35, 14] 18,496 │ │ └─ReLU: 3-8 [128, 64, 35, 14] -- │ │ └─MaxPool2d: 3-9 [128, 64, 17, 7] -- ├─convblock: 1-4 [128, 128, 9, 4] -- │ └─Sequential: 2-4 [128, 128, 9, 4] -- │ │ └─Conv2d: 3-10 [128, 128, 19, 9] 73,856 │ │ └─ReLU: 3-11 [128, 128, 19, 9] -- │ │ └─MaxPool2d: 3-12 [128, 128, 9, 4] -- ├─Flatten: 1-5 [128, 4608] -- ├─Linear: 1-6 [128, 10] 46,090 ├─Softmax: 1-7 [128, 10] -- ==========================================================================================
Total params: 143,242 Trainable params: 143,242 Non-trainable params: 0 Total mult-adds (G): 3.</description></item><item><title>Forests and Deforestation</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/visualisation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 09:23:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/visualisation/</guid><description>Synopsis In this project we explore the trends of deforestation in the past 3 decades. We use visualisation techniques in order to find patterns behind deforestation and it&amp;rsquo;s driving factors. Following this, we attempt to answer questions regarding conversion of forests to land for other purposes and questions regarding Brazil&amp;rsquo;s excessive loss of forest cover. Then we aim to develop a dashboard to explore the above posed questions.
Links GitHub: deforestation-and-forest-conversion</description></item><item><title>Financial Literacy among 18-35 year olds</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/financial-literacy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 22:27:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/financial-literacy/</guid><description>Synopsis We conduct a survey where we test the respondent&amp;rsquo;s knowledge on 4 aspenct: financial knowledge and skills, financial attitude and knowledge about inflation and other parameters. Using these we attempt to judge their financial literacy.
This project is being conducted by by 5 first year MSc. Data Science students at the Chennai Mathematical Institute: Me, Adarsha Mondal, Shreyan Chakraborty, Deepmalya Dutta and Ujan Dasgputa.
The project is in progress. More information will be added at a later point of time.</description></item><item><title>Bayesian Analysis of Efficacy of the ChAd0x1 nCoV-19 (AZD1222) Vaccine</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/dissertation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 22:00:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://roudranil.github.io/projects/dissertation/</guid><description>Synopsis 2020 saw the onset of the onset of the Covid-19 pandemic cause by the SARS-CoV-2 virus. With the number of daily affected people and number of deaths due to the pandemic climbing sharply, a vaccine was the need of the hour. In this paper we consider one such vaccine, the ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 (AZD1222) vaccine (known as Covishield in India), and we investigate its efficacy based on studies of four randomised controlled trials held in Brazil, South Africa, and the United Kingdom.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roudranil.github.io/about/</guid><description>Introduction I am Roudranil Das, a first year MSc. Data Science student at the Chennai Mathematical Institute, India and I did my bachelors in Mathematics from St. Xavier&amp;rsquo;s College, Kolkata.
I am interested in the applications of AI/ML in the financial sector. Lately I have taken a keen interest in audio signal processing for Machine Learning and application of DL models for audio detection and other use cases.
Besides, I am also a musician!</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://roudranil.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roudranil.github.io/contact/</guid><description>You can reach out to me via mail at roudranil@cmi.ac.in.
You can also hit me up on Discord at Rudy#3402.
Feel free to connect with me on LinkedIn.</description></item></channel></rss>